DANTE XYSTUS

www.linkedin.com/in/dantexystus

dantex99@gmail.com

Chicago, IL

Portfolio

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Innovative tech mind with extensive experience in game engines and software implementation. Lead UI programmer for an online robotic combat game released in August 2021. Able to quickly understand existing code and suggest improvements. Lived in Asia, U.S., and the Middle East. Experienced in working with culturally diverse teams.

EXPERIENCE

PROGRAMMER | T'SARE

APRIL 2023 - CURRENT

- Collaborated with Lead programmer to create tools for efficient content generation.
- · Utilized source control for codebase updates.
- Designed and built systems to enhance User Experience
- Took initiative by proactively integrating the development of accessibility features within the project.

INSTRUCTOR | IDTECH

JUNE 2019-CURRENT

- Taught programming courses (Python, Unity, and Game Design) in both face-toface and virtual environments and to groups with wide ranging experience levels.
- Defined key learning objectives with stakeholders and obtained desirable student outcomes through focused, individualized attention.
- Coached and mentored each student to design challenging final projects that showcased their learning.

LEAD UI PROGRAMMER | JUNKPUNK ARENA

JAN 2021-AUGUST 2021

- Designed UI pipeline which improved productivity by 40%.
- Prioritized and scoped feature requests to ensure that the biggest impact features were worked on first.
- Programmed custom tools to enable designers to quickly iterate on key features.
- Quickly grasped the current codebase during the on-boarding process and identified key areas for improvement.
- Front-End Development: UI/UX, identifying and extracting variables to expose into existing systems.
- Back-End Development: Data Structures, Algorithms.

EDUCATION

CHAMPLAIN COLLEGE | BURLINGTON, VERMONT, U.S.A

Bachelor of Computer Science - Game Programming

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Agile, C, C#, C++, CSS, Figma, Git, HTML, Java, Javascript, Python, UI/UX, Unity, Unreal Engine

SOFT SKILLS

Teaching and coaching; Designing educational curriculums for programming courses; Learning new computer languages.